<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devops on Light Java - The fastest Java API Framework</title>
    <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/devops/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devops on Light Java - The fastest Java API Framework</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Released under the MIT license</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 20:55:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://networknt.github.io/light-java/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 20:55:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/devops/linux_service/&#34;&gt;How to deploy standalone microservices as Linux service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/devops/windows_service/&#34;&gt;How to deploy standalone microservices as Windows service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Light-Java Application as Linux Service</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/devops/linux_service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 08:03:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/devops/linux_service/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Light-Java application can be easily started as Unix/Linux services using either init.d or systemd given it
is packaged as a fatjar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation-as-an-init-d-service-system-v&#34;&gt;Installation as an init.d service (System V)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your application is packaged as a fatjar, and you’re not using a custom script, then your application
can be used as an init.d service. Simply symlink the jar to init.d to support the standard start, stop,
restart and status commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script supports the following features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starts the services as the user that owns the jar file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tracks application’s PID using /var/run/&lt;appname&gt;/&lt;appname&gt;.pid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writes console logs to /var/log/&lt;appname&gt;.log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming that you have a Light Java application installed in /var/myapp, to install the application as an
init.d service simply create a symlink:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo ln -s /var/myapp/myapp.jar /etc/init.d/myapp
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once installed, you can start and stop the service in the usual way. For example, on a Debian based system:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;service myapp start
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also flag the application to start automatically using your standard operating system tools. For
example, on Debian:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;update-rc.d myapp defaults &amp;lt;priority&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;securing-an-init-d-service&#34;&gt;Securing an init.d service&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When executed as root, as is the case when root is being used to start an init.d service, the default
executable script will run the application as the user which owns the jar file. You should never run
a Light Java application as root so your application’s jar file should never be owned by root. Instead,
create a specific user to run your application and use chown to make it the owner of the jar file. For
example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;chown bootapp:bootapp your-app.jar
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, the default executable script will run the application as the bootapp user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reduce the chances of the application’s user account being compromised, you should consider preventing
it from using a login shell. Set the account’s shell to /usr/sbin/nologin, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also take steps to prevent the modification of your application’s jar file. Firstly, configure
its permissions so that it cannot be written and can only be read or executed by its owner:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;chmod 500 your-app.jar
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, you should also take steps to limit the damage if your application or the account that’s running
it is compromised. If an attacker does gain access, they could make the jar file writable and change its
contents. One way to protect against this is to make it immutable using chattr:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chattr +i your-app.jar
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will prevent any user, including root, from modifying the jar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;f root is used to control the application’s service and you use a .conf file to customize its startup,
the .conf file will be read and evaluated by the root user. It should be secured accordingly. Use chmod
so that the file can only be read by the owner and use chown to make root the owner:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;chmod 400 your-app.conf
sudo chown root:root your-app.conf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Light-Java Application as Windows Service</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/devops/windows_service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 08:03:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/devops/windows_service/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Light-Java is packaged as a fatjar and normally will be running in docker container
on production; however, it can be executed on Windows or Linux host machine or VM
with the following command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;java -jar filename.jar
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For production deployment, you want to make sure that when you host server/VM
is restarted, the application will be restarted automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following describes step-by-step how you can create a Windows service for your
Light-Java application or any Java application that can be packaged in a fatjar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two different options but the first option is more generic and popular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;windows-service-wrapper&#34;&gt;Windows Service Wrapper&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to difficulties with the GPL license of the Java Service Wrapper
(the second option below) in combination with e.g. the MIT license of Jenkins,
the Windows Service Wrapper project, also known as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kohsuke/winsw&#34;&gt;winsw&lt;/a&gt;,
is the best choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winsw provides programmatic means to install/uninstall/start/stop a service. In
addition, it may be used to run any kind of executable as a service under Windows,
whereas Java Service Wrapper, as implied by its name, only supports Java applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you download the binaries &lt;a href=&#34;http://repo.jenkins-ci.org/releases/com/sun/winsw/winsw/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, the configuration file that defines our Windows service, MyApp.xml, should
look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;service&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;id&amp;gt;MyApp&amp;lt;/id&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;MyApp&amp;lt;/name&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;description&amp;gt;This runs Spring Boot as a Service.&amp;lt;/description&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;env name=&amp;quot;MYAPP_HOME&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;%BASE%&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;executable&amp;gt;java&amp;lt;/executable&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;arguments&amp;gt;-Xmx256m -jar &amp;quot;%BASE%\MyApp.jar&amp;quot;&amp;lt;/arguments&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;logmode&amp;gt;rotate&amp;lt;/logmode&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/service&amp;gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you have to rename the winsw.exe to MyApp.exe so that its name matches
with the MyApp.xml configuration file. Thereafter you can install the service
like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ MyApp.exe install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, you may use uninstall, start, stop, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;java-service-wrapper&#34;&gt;Java Service Wrapper&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you don’t mind the GPL licensing of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wrapper.tanukisoftware.com/doc/english/index.html&#34;&gt;Java Service Wrapper&lt;/a&gt;
project, this alternative may address your needs to configure your JAR file as
a Windows service equally well. Basically, the Java Service Wrapper also requires
you to specify in a configuration file which specifies how to run your process
as a service under Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://edn.embarcadero.com/article/32068&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; explains in a very
detailed way how to set up such an execution of a JAR file as a service under
Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>