<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Architectures on Light Java - The fastest Java API Framework</title>
    <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architectures on Light Java - The fastest Java API Framework</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Released under the MIT license</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 14:41:29 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Nodejs Pitfalls</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/nodejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 14:41:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/nodejs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When talking about microservices, a lot of Nodejs developers will say that
Node is a better platform than Java and other languages to build microservices.
The arguments are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nodejs is faster than Java at runtime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nodejs development is more productive than Java.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These claims are proved to be false already as I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on both
platforms in banking industry for the last couple of years. I have been
building REST API frameworks on both Java and Nodejs and the following are
my observations on Nodejs in enterprise computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;production-hell&#34;&gt;Production hell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As workers are single-threaded, any uncaught exception will crash the worker
and all the in-flight transactions will be lost and you don&amp;rsquo;t know what is
the state of each in-flight request. This is the biggest problem faced and
I have worked with several core Nodejs developers trying to mitigate the risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end result is to capture it in the server.js and then wait for in-flight
to complete as many as possible in a unknown state of the server and then
shutdown the server. Not ideal but it reduce the risk to certain level. Due to
this reason, Nodejs API platform is only recommended for readonly API in the
bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Node server crashes under load (cpu 90% or up). We found this during out loaded
test with Winston logger enabled and the server always dead without any response
after a while. The reason is these callbacks don&amp;rsquo;t have enough cpu time to
complete and there are piling up in memory until you run out of memory, the server
won&amp;rsquo;t shutdown in this situation but simply won&amp;rsquo;t respond. The solution for
us is to monitor the cpu usage and starting more containers when it is in
heavy load.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;callback-hell&#34;&gt;Callback Hell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is know issue for Javascript. Although promise helps a lot, it is still a
big issue with Node platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-maintenance&#34;&gt;Code Maintenance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nodejs is easy to get into and very fast to build small Hello World application;
however, building complex enterprise level application with thousands of line of
code is very hard. When I look at my own code wrote one year ago, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t
reason about what that piece code does. I have to put some debug info and run it
to figure out how the code works. Callback Hell is one of the causes. For
enterprise applications, easy to understand and maintain is very important and I
feel sorry for the bank employees who have taken over my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;debugging&#34;&gt;Debugging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Javascript as a platform doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a good runtime debugging tool that you can inspect
variables during runtime easily. There are some tools but none of them works as
good as other languages. I use a customized logger built by myself and put a lot
of logging statement in order to debug my code and I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so many js developers
just use console.log:)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-transaction-support&#34;&gt;No Transaction Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No transaction support on the platform makes it not enterprise ready. Let&amp;rsquo;s say
you are building a stock order API, once the server receives the request, it needs
to save the order in backend database and route the order to an exchange for execution.
what if the communication to Exchange is down? There is no way that the local
database update can be rolled back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lack-of-connectivity-to-backend-system&#34;&gt;Lack of Connectivity to Backend System&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the above order API, the order has to be routed to an exchange through MQ Queue
but node didn&amp;rsquo;t support it 2 years ago. Also, a lot of existing backend
systems and databases are not supported even today. I have worked with Strongloop
and IBM teams for three months to make IBM DB2
drive(&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ibmdb/node-ibm_db&#34;&gt;https://github.com/ibmdb/node-ibm_db&lt;/a&gt;) worked on production without
memory leak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;insufficient-of-module-and-version-management&#34;&gt;Insufficient of Module and Version Management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people praises npm and I agree that it is very good tool to manage modules.
However, only manage modules is no enough, it has to manage modules with versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most Node developers will have this experience. You have an application running today
and tomorrow, you run npm install again and it stops working:) As one of the dependencies
got a new version and it is not backward compatible. Shrinkwrap helps a little bit but
it is very hard to update one or two immediate dependent modules as there is no way to
update sub dependencies. Another way is to check in node_modules into git and packaged it
into docker container. Now we always package node_modules into docker image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;windows-un-friendly&#34;&gt;Windows Un-Friendly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;while trying to check in node_modules folder into git on Windows platform, most cases
you will get an error as some files are buried too deep in the directory and Windows
has limitation on path length. This issue has been partially fixed in later version
of Node as npm tries to flatten all the dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the modules depending on C/C++ that cannot be compiled on Windows. It causes
issues for teams that use different platforms for development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given Windows is not case sensitive on file names, application developed on Windows
usually cannot be executed on Linux the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;long-running-process-hogs-cpu&#34;&gt;Long Running process hogs CPU&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a problem of Nodejs but mistake of developers. I have seen too many this
kind of mistakes and I want to highlight it here. As node is using event loop
to dispatch tasks/callbacks, if any callback designed wrongly and doesn&amp;rsquo;t give up CPU
for a period of time, the entire system will suffer. If you have to process thousands
of records loaded from database, process them in 100 blocks. There are so many articles
talking about this topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;public-module-quality&#34;&gt;Public Module Quality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No doubt there is a very active community for Nodejs and there are a lot of modules published
on public npm repository. I myself got several modules published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there are so many modules are in bad shape as developers of these modules
often migrated from frontend without any enterprise level experience. Some of modules got
10 line of the code but will depending on 8 other modules. Write a small express application
in nodejs and take a look at how many modules in node_modules folder. Is you application
using them all? I guess less than 5 percent of the code in node_modules are in the
execution path and the rest of them are just wasting your hard drive space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A legendary Node developer TJ mentioned the same reason in his farewell article
regarding to modules. Javascript sets the bar very low and it attracts a lot of low level
developers. Remember Visual Basic was the most popular language on Microsoft platform?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stability-of-the-platform&#34;&gt;Stability of the Platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one bank I worked last year, they are still using Nodejs 0.10.39 as that was the only
production ready version. Both Strongloop and Joyent told us to stay on that version and as
I understand, other customers are on the same version. We were told to upgrade to 0.12.x
once it was prouduction ready and then Nodejs and IO.js were merged and Nodejs 4 was out.
Before Nodejs 4 was production ready, they&amp;rsquo;ve moved to Nodejs 5 and now on Nodejs 6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are having big issue with Nodejs 0.10.39 as https module is not performing with API to
API calls and the issue was resolved in 0.12.x. So our recommendation for Nodejs API
framework added another condition upon only readonly API - The API must not call another
API in https. All APIs that calling another API with https must be implemented in Java
framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;talents-abandoned-the-ship&#34;&gt;Talents abandoned the ship&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you might know, TJ who is the developer of express - most popular nodejs framework left
Nodejs to GO. Here is his &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@tjholowaychuk/farewell-node-js-4ba9e7f3e52b#.5brqa9has&#34;&gt;farewell&lt;/a&gt;
There are other heavy weight Nodejs developers left and that might make you think what
is going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;existing-customers-are-stuck-or-leaving&#34;&gt;Existing Customers are stuck or leaving&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some early adopters of Nodejs and all of them are trapped with old version of Nodejs
and they are so afraid to upgrade to the new version as memory leak will be hard to
resolve - refer to my production hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other companies, just rewrite the application with other language. One example is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@theflapjack103/the-way-of-the-gopher-6693db15ae1f#.jfcsl8hlg&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the bank I&amp;rsquo;ve worked, they wrote some APIs in Nodejs in 2014 but most of them were rewritten
in Java in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;memory-footprint-is-high-on-multiple-core-platform&#34;&gt;Memory Footprint is high on multiple core platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one worker, it uses less memory than Java, but on a multi-core system, you have to start
workers per cpu core in order to utilize the resource to its full potential. These workers
are independent and there is no shared memory, they allocate heap independently. If you start
four or eight workers, it uses more memory than Java which has only one instance multi-threaded
with shared heap memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;much-slower-than-new-java-platforms&#34;&gt;Much slower than New Java platforms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for speed, it is faster than WebSphere/WebLogic/JBoss but not in the same level as other
new containerless Java frameworks and platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/networknt/light-java-example/tree/master/performance&#34;&gt;benchmarks&lt;/a&gt;
that have both popular Java microservices frameworks and Nodejs/Express. The above performance
result only focus on raw throughput and latency. While more code is added, Nodejs will be
getting slower and slower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work on both Nodejs and Java so my opinion is not biased but to point out the facts on
Nodejs platform. No doubt you can build rock solid Nodejs application with a group of senior
developers but it is very hard to find that level of developers. I am not saying Java is
better as I know there are a lot of issues with Java. I just hope these points will help
you in choosing your next application platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Patterns</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 20:55:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/integration/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;While working with my clients to transform monolithic Java EE applications to
microservices architecture, one of the most frequently asked questions from
my clients is how do you integrate your newly built microservices with existing
Java EE applications. In other words, how to leverage existing application
stacks when exposing REST APIs with microservices?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most organizations especially financial institutions, they have big Java
EE applications running on Weblogic/Websphere that they&amp;rsquo;ve invested efforts
for a decade or longer. You cannot image that they can rewrite everything and
switch to microservices overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been working the following four different approaches over the last 5
years and I will give my recommendations based on my experience. Please be
aware that this is just a generic recommendation and it cannot be applied
to all use cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;api-gateway&#34;&gt;API Gateway&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most commercial API gateways offer the XML to JSON and JSON to XML
transformation feature and this was good selling point to in early days. They
promised that you buy their product and the gateway will transform your
XML based web services to JSON based REST APIs. The problem with this
approach is performance, as all of them provide a generic transformer working
with external defined mapping logic. The transformation is CPU intensive and
with the overhead of gateway security and other layers, the throughput and
latency are not acceptable. Also, there are other issues with commercial
gateways as I documented at &lt;a href=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/gateway/&#34;&gt;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/gateway/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;customized-transformation-in-api&#34;&gt;Customized Transformation in API&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some developers and architects realized that buying a gateway cannot resolve
the problem magically so they tried to build the transform logic into the API
itself. The transformation code is customized per API and it is much more
efficient that generic transformer in gateways. This provide a little bit
more flexibility and a little bit increased performance but it is not easy
to write the transform code as most web services have very complicated request
and response schemas. Performance wise, it is better than commercial gateway
solutions but still very bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;calling-service-layer-behind-soa-or-emb&#34;&gt;Calling service layer behind SOA or EMB&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most web services are built with multiple layers and chances are you have
a service layer behind your web service tier with Java native APIs. In this
case, we can bypass web services and calling the native Java API (most likely
session beans) from your REST APIs. This gives us a relative good performance
and leverage the most complicated services in the application tier. It is also
a low cost solution to bring REST API on top of your existing applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only drawback is that these app layers are deployed on Java EE platform
and they have limited throughput and very hard to be scaled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;calling-book-of-record-directly&#34;&gt;Calling Book of Record directly&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to fully realize the benefits of microservices architecture, the
existing monolithic application must be rewritten so that microservices can
talk to the book of record directly. And this can be done during a long period
of time to break up existing system to function areas and convert them one by
one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As describe above, it is recommended to rewrite the existing monolithic app
but if resources are constrained, then build microservices by calling
existing services are acceptable. As microserivces can be individually deployed
and replaced, it is easy to convert them all to the final stage one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 21:13:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/monitoring/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Monitoring used to be a somewhat passive thing. You used tools to monitor the
application process/logs and perhaps send an alert if something seemed wrong,&lt;br /&gt;
but mostly it was hands off. When we move to microservices architecture, things
are changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;user-experience-and-microservices-monitoring&#34;&gt;User Experience and Microservices Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Microservices which are released more often, you can try new features and
see how they impact user usage patterns. With this feedback, you can improve
your application. It is not uncommon to employ A/B testing and multi-variant
testing to try out new combinations of features. Monitoring is more than just
watching for failure. With big data, data science, and microservices,
monitoring microservices runtime stats is required to know your application
users. You want to know what your users like and dislike and react.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;debugging-and-microservices-monitoring&#34;&gt;Debugging and Microservices Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Runtime statistics and metrics are critical for distributed systems. Since
microservices architecture use a lot of remote calls. Monitoring microservices
metrics can include request per second, available memory, #threads, #connections,
failed authentication, expired tokens, etc. These parameters are important for
understanding and debugging your code. Working with distributed systems is hard.
Working with distributed systems without reactive monitoring is crazy. Reactive
monitoring allows you to react to failure conditions and ramp of services for
higher loads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;circuit-breaker-and-microservices-monitoring&#34;&gt;Circuit Breaker and Microservices Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can employ the Circuit Breaker pattern to prevent a catastrophic cascade,
and reactive microservices monitoring can be the trigger. Downstream services
can be registered in a service discovery so that you can mark nodes as unhealthy
as well react by reroute in the case of outages. The reaction can be serving up
a deprecated version of the data or service, but the key is to avoid cascading
failure. You don&amp;rsquo;t want your services falling over like dominoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cloud-orchestration-and-microservices-monitoring&#34;&gt;Cloud Orchestration and Microservices Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reactive microservices monitoring would enable you to detect heavy load, and
spin up new instances with the cloud orchestration platform of your choice
(EC2, CloudStack, OpenStack, Rackspace, boto, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;public-microservices-and-microservices-monitoring&#34;&gt;Public Microservices and Microservices Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microservices monitoring of runtime statistics can be used to rate limiting
a partners Application ID. You don&amp;rsquo;t want partners to consume all of your
well-tuned, high-performant microservices resources. It is okay to trust your
partners but use Microservices Monitoring to verify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monitoring public microservices is your way to verify. Once you make microservices
publicly available or partner available, you have to monitor and rate limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a new concept. If you have ever used a public REST API from Google for
example, you are well aware of rate limiting. A rate limit will do things like limit
the number of connections you’re allowed to make. It is common for rate limits to
limit the number of certain requests that a client id or partner id is allowed to
make in a given time period. This is protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deploying public or partner accessible microservices without this protection is
lunacy and a recipe for disaster, unless you like failing when someone decides to
hit your endpoints 10x more than you did the capacity planning for. Avoid long
nights and tears. Monitor microservices that you publish, and limit access to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reactive manifesto is a good tutor for the types of monitoring you will want
to do and states that your system should react to change instead of just fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;microservices-framework-and-microservices-monitoring&#34;&gt;Microservices Framework and Microservices Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Light-Java a mircoservices framework that comes with a runtime metrics which can
be used for Microservices Monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can query /server/health endpoint to detect if the service is available and healthy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The framework collects metrics info and pushes it into influxdb and dashboard can be viewed from Grafana.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rate limiting can be enabled at client_id level or ip address/user level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubernetes monitors load of each pods and can start new instances on demand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TraceabilityId and CorrelationId in logs that can be traced with tools like Logstash, GrayLog and Splunk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reactive-microservices-monitoring&#34;&gt;Reactive Microservices Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reactive Microservices Monitoring is an essential ingredient of microservices architecture.
You need it for debugging, knowing your users, working with partners, building reactive
systems that react to load and failures without cascading outages. Reactive Microservices
Monitoring can not be a hindsight decision. Build your microservices with microservices
monitoring in mind from the start. Make sure that the microservices lib that you use has
monitoring of runtime statistics built in from the start. Make sure that is a core part of
the microservices library. Code Hale Statistics allow you to gather metrics in
a standard way. Tools like Influxdb and Grafana, Kibana help you understand the
data, and build dashboards. Light Java, the Java Microservices Framework, includes a metrics
middleware which feeds into CodeHale Metrics. Light Java also proivdes a rate limiting
middleware to limit access per client_id or IP address/user. The container orchestration tool
like Kubernetes can also spin up new nodes/pods. With big data, data science,
and microservices, monitoring microservices runtime stats is required to know your application
users, know your partners, know what your system will do under load, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;microservice-logging&#34;&gt;Microservice Logging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every instance of the service will have a unique identifier which most commonly will be
the docker container name or the hostname if not deployed in docker container. The code
to retrieve docker container name and hostname is the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with docker container name, traceabilityId and correlationId will be logged as
context info for each logging statement. And once log files are aggregated together in
ELK, users can trace a particular transaction based on the traceabilityId or correlationId.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As microservices might be deployed across multiple geo-regions, the timestamp logged must
be UTC time so that logs can be easily ordered in the ELK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;microservice-alerting&#34;&gt;Microservice Alerting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logstash has features to send out alert when certain error code is spotted in the log files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The framework has a component called status and it has all the errors defined in a JSON
file which can be externalized. All the error code will be in a format ERRXXXXX and
certain error code can be setup in the alert to send out email or communicate to support
team with other channels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>traceability</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/traceability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 11:04:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/traceability/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For microservices architecture, it is very important to trace request from one service to
another in the entire call tree in order to have big picture if something happens or have
an audit log that is aggregated by database or Splunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the framework, we have two Ids to serve this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;x-traceability-id&#34;&gt;X-Traceability-Id&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generated by client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unique for this client only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be database sequence number or UUID&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must be passed to the next service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must be returned to the caller&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will be logged in per request audit log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;x-correlation-id&#34;&gt;X-Correlation-Id&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generated in the immediate service from client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must be UUID&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must be passed to the next service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will be logged in per request audit log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every service/API must check if this id available and generate one if doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist in request header.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;pass-ids-to-the-next-service-api&#34;&gt;Pass Ids to the next service/API&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to pass these ids to the next service, the call to the next service
must use Client module provided by the framework. It will put these ids to
the HttpRequest header with method calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hers is an example to set JWT tokens, traceabilityId and correlationId&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;recommended-log-analysis-tool&#34;&gt;Recommended Log Analysis Tool&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elastic.co/products/logstash&#34;&gt;ELK/Logstash (Open Source)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Graylog2/graylog2-server&#34;&gt;Graylog (Open Source with commercial version)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.splunk.com/&#34;&gt;Splunk (Commercial)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Architecture</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 17:22:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/plugin/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In the framework design, we have adopted the same principal of microservices architecture to break
down the entire framework into smaller pieces so that each can be customized and replaced if
necessary. The only difference is that all the modules in the framework are wired in request/response
chain for best performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/images/light_java_component.png&#34; alt=&#34;component&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four type of components that can be wired in at different stage of the server start up. The
following is the loading sequence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Startup Hook Providers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shutdown Hook Providers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handler Provider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Middleware Handlers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/images/startup_sequence.png&#34; alt=&#34;startup_sequence&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;plugin-implementation&#34;&gt;Plugin implementation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many way to implement plugins and wire in different implementations of the same
interface. Spring is one of the popular ways. However, it will make our framework depending on
a version of spring framework and that can cause a lot of problems if the API handlers are
using different version of spring framework. Also, we don&amp;rsquo;t want to make the framework depending
on spring and force everyone to include it. In the end, we are using Java SPI
(Service Provider Interface). In your generated API project, you can find four files in
/src/main/resources/META-INF/services. These files contains plugins to be loaded/executed during
server startup and shutdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;shutdown-hook-providers&#34;&gt;Shutdown Hook Providers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shutdown hook providers are plugins that would be called during server shutdown in order to release
resources. For example, close database connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All shutdown hook providers will implement interface com.networknt.server.ShutdownHookProvider&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;public interface ShutdownHookProvider {
    void onShutdown();
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The onShutdown() in your implementation will be called before server shutdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;startup-hook-providers&#34;&gt;Startup Hook Providers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startup hook providers are plugins that would be called during server startup in order to initialize
resources. For example, create database connection pool, load spring application context etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All startup hook providers will implement interface com.networknt.server.StartupHookProvider&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;public interface StartupHookProvider {
    void onStartup();
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The onStartup() in your implementation will be called before server startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;handler-provider&#34;&gt;Handler Provider&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is only one handler provider that is needed to wire in API implementations. In most of the
cases, it would be an instance of io.undertow.server.RoutingHandler just like the generated &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/networknt/light-java-example/tree/master/petstore&#34;&gt;petstore
project&lt;/a&gt;. However, it is not
limited and it can be several handlers chained together. One example is the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/networknt/light-java-example/tree/master/webserver&#34;&gt;webserver example&lt;/a&gt; and it
has several handlers chained together to provide API routing as well as static website. The handler
provide code can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/networknt/light-java-example/blob/master/webserver/src/main/java/com/networknt/webserver/handler/WebServerHandlerProvider.java&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have OpenAPI specification defined, this handler provider will be generated from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/networknt/swagger-codegen&#34;&gt;swagger-codegen&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/networknt/light-java-example/blob/master/petstore/src/main/java/io/swagger/handler/PathHandlerProvider.java&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;
is a generated petstore handler provider that has the mapping for all endpoints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handler provider implements interface com.networknt.server.HandlerProvider&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;public interface HandlerProvider {
    HttpHandler getHandler();
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The getHandler() will return an HttpHandler or a chain of HttpHandlers wrapped together. This handler
will be called in the request/response chain right after all middleware handlers are called.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;middleware-handlers&#34;&gt;Middleware Handlers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some &lt;a href=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/middleware/&#34;&gt;builtin middleware components&lt;/a&gt;
in the framework to address common cross cutting concerns. There are implemented in a way we think
the best to meet most of business requirements. In other words, there are opinionated. For product
that built top of the framework, you can add/customize/replace existing middleware handlers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All middleware handlers need to implement interface com.networknt.handler.MiddlewareHandler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;public interface MiddlewareHandler extends HttpHandler {

    HttpHandler getNext();

    MiddlewareHandler setNext(final HttpHandler next);

    boolean isEnabled();

    void register();

}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;boolean isEnabled()&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every middleware handler has a corresponding config file which is the same name lower case
with .json extension. There must be flag to indicate if the handle will be wired in during
server startup. This gives user a chance to temporary disable a particular middleware handler
without changing the SPI configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;void register()&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This function will be called when the middleware is wired in the request/response chain. It registers
itself and configuration to server info component which can be accessed through a special endpoint
to get runtime information on middleware handlers and their configuration along with other system
info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MiddlewareHandler setNext(final HttpHandler next)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As middleware handler are chained together, so the existing handler must be put in the current
handler as next. When the current handler is completed, it will call the next handler if there is
no error. And eventually, the user provided handler will be called if all middleware handler are
completed without an error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-sequence-of-middleware-handlers&#34;&gt;The sequence of middleware handlers.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are dependencies between middleware handlers so the sequence to plug them in is very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For default plugins generated from &lt;a href=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/tools/swagger-codegen/&#34;&gt;swagger-codegen&lt;/a&gt;,
please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/other/server/&#34;&gt;Server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;diagram&#34;&gt;Diagram&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/images/handler_chain.png&#34; alt=&#34;handler_chain&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that audit, metrics and exception need to hooked in the response in order to handle exceptions
on both request and response phase, calculate response time and dump response info into the audit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 14:34:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/security/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Note: If this is the first time you hear about OAuth2 or you want to get familiar with
the grant types we are using, please read this
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/networknt/undertow-oauth2/wiki/OAuth2-Introduction&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone’s excited about microservices, but actual implementation is sparse. Perhaps the
reason is that people are unclear on how these services talk to one another; especially
tricky is access management throughout a sea of independent services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While designing microserivces, big monolithic application is breaking down to smaller
services that can be independently deployed or replaced. The final application will have
more http calls than a single application, how can we protect these calls between services?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To protect APIs/services, the answer is OAuth2 and most simple and popular solution will be
simple web token as access token. The client authenticates itself on OAuth2 server and OAuth2
server issues
a simple web token (a UUID in most of the cases), then the client sends the request to API
server with access token in the Authorization header. Once API server receives the request,
it has to send the access token to OAuth2 server to verify if this is valid token and if
this token is allowed to access this API. As you can see there must be a database lookup on
OAuth2 server to do that. Distributed cache help a lot but there is still a network call and
lookup for every single request. OAuth2 server eventually becomes a bottleneck and a single
point of failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years ago, when JWT draft specification was out, I came up with the idea to do the
distributed security verification with JWT to replace Simple Web Token for one of the big
banks in Canada. At that time, there was nobody using JWT this way and the bank sent the design to
Paul Madson and John Bradley who are the Authors of OAuth2 and JWT specifications and got
their endorsements to use JWT this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;distributed-jwt-verification&#34;&gt;Distributed JWT Verification&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the diagram of distributed JWT verification for microservices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/images/ms_distributed_jwt.png&#34; alt=&#34;ms_distributed_jwt&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s assume the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client1 is a web server and it has client1 as client_id.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API A is a microservice and it has apia as client_id and it requires a.r scope to access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API B is a microserivce and it has apib as client_id and it requires b.r scope to access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API C is a microservice and it has apic as client_id and it requires c.r scope to access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API D is a microservice and it has apid as client_id and it requires d.r scope to access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;user-trigger-the-authentication&#34;&gt;User trigger the authentication&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When user clicks the login button or accesses resource that is protected, he will be
redirect to OAuth2 server to authenticate himself. After input username and password, an
authorization code is redirected back to the browser. The client1 will handle the redirect
url and get the authorization code. By sending client1 client_id, client_secret and
authorization code from user to OAuth2 server, Client1 gets a JWT token with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;user_id = user1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;client_id = client1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;scope = [a.r]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This token will be put into the Authorization header of the request to API A. When API A
receives the request, it verifies the JWT token with public key issued by OAuth2 server with
the security middleware in the framework. If the signature verification is successful, it
will verify the scope in the token against the swagger specification defined for the
endpoint Client1 is accessing. As a.r is required and it is in the JWT scope, it allows
the access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;api-a-calls-api-b-and-api-c&#34;&gt;API A calls API B and API C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now API A needs to call API B and API C to fulfill the request. As this is API to API call or
service to service call, there is no user id involved and Client Credentials flow will be
used here to get another JWT token to B and C. The original JWT token doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the scopes
to access B and C as Client1 does not even care A is calling B and C. So here API A needs to
get a token associate with client_id apia which has proper scope to access API B and API C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This token will have the following claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;client_id = apia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;scope = [b.r c.r]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the original token has the original user_id, it is carried in the entire service to service
calls so that each service has a chance to do role based or user based authorization if it is
necessary. The new client_credentials token will be passed in the request header &amp;ldquo;X-Scope-Token&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;api-b-and-api-c-tokens-verification&#34;&gt;API B and API C tokens verification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tokens verification on API B and API C are the same. So le&amp;rsquo;t use API B as an example to
explain the verification process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When API B receives the request, it first check the Authorization token to make sure it is valid. Then
if scope verification is enabled, it will check if &amp;lsquo;X-Scope-Token&amp;rsquo; header exists. If yes, it will verify
it and match the scope with endpoint defined scope. If scope matching is failed, it will fall back
to Authorization token to see if it has the scope required. If none of the tokens has the scope required,
an error will be sent back to the caller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;api-b-calls-api-d&#34;&gt;API B calls API D&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process is very similar like API A calls API B and API C. A client credentials token will be
retrieved by API B from OAuth2 server and it has the following claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;client_id = apib&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;scope = [d.r]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;api-d-token-verification&#34;&gt;API D token verification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar like API B and API C tokens verification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;client-credentials-scope-token-cache&#34;&gt;Client Credentials / Scope Token Cache&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As described above, for every API to API call, the caller must pass in a scope token in addition to
the original token. Unlike the original token which is associated with a user, the scope token is only
associated with a client (API / service) and it won&amp;rsquo;t be expired after a period configured on OAuth2
server. So it is not necessary to get the new scope token for every API to API call. The token is
retrieved and cached in memory until it is about to be expired then a new token will be retrieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire token renew process is managed
by &lt;a href=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/other/client/&#34;&gt;Client&lt;/a&gt; module provided in the light-java
framework. This client module encapsulate a lot of features to help API to API calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;authorization-token-cache&#34;&gt;Authorization Token Cache&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original token normally will be cached in the web server session so that the subsequent calls
from the same user can use the cached token.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;single-sign-on&#34;&gt;Single Sign On&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the end user login is managed by OAuth2 server, there is a session established between user&amp;rsquo;s
browser and OAuth2 server. The the user switch to another tab on his browser to access another
application, the login on OAuth2 is not necessary and a new authorization code will immediately
redirected back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Gateway</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 14:33:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/gateway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When your organization is thinking about breaking up the big monolithic
application to adopt microservices architecture, chances are there are
some vendors coming to sell their gateway solutions. Why they want to
sell you gateways and do you really need a gateway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason they are eagerly selling you a gateway is because they have
to monetize their product as soon as possible before it is obsolete.
The solutions they provided are not truely microservices as there is
no standalone gateway in the picture of the real microservices
architecture. Their solution is coming from web services(SOA) design
and all services behind the gateway are flattened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a picture of their typical solution in the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/images/ms_oauth2_gateway.png&#34; alt=&#34;ms_oauth2_gateway&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After awhile, they realized that for every request from client, there
are two calls from client and api to OAuth2 server and remote calls
are too heavy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the solution for gateway vendors is to move OAuth2 server inside
the gateway so that there is no remote calls between gateway and OAuth2
server for security verification. Here is an updated gateway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/images/ms_oauth2_in_gateway.png&#34; alt=&#34;ms_oauth2_in_gateway&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With increasing volume, the monolithic gateway becomes bottleneck and
the only solutions is horizontal scaling. That means you have a cluster
of gateway instances and gateway becomes a single point of failure. If
any component fails in gateway, all your APIs are not accessible. It is
also very hard to scale as it is a big application with a lot of
components built in and uses a lot of CPU and memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you look inside the APIs protected by the gateway, you can see
these APIs are implemented in JavaEE containers like
WebLogic/WebSphere/JBoss/SpringBoot etc. and they don&amp;rsquo;t call each
other. They are simply monolithic JavaEE application packaged in ear
or war and exposed REST APIs. These APIs are normally deployed in Data
Centers and lately moved to cloud. They are not real microservices at
all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some smart developers attempted to break these big application into
smaller pieces and move into the direction of microservices but gateway
became a problem. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at how API to API call looks like
with gateway in the following diagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/images/ms_gateway_api_to_api.png&#34; alt=&#34;ms_gateway_api_to_api&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, when API A calls API B, although both of them are behind
the gateway, the request has to go in front of gateway to properly
authenticate/authorize the request. Clearly, the centralized gateway
design is against the decentralized principle of microservices
architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our framework, the solution is to move all the cross cutting concerns
to the API framework and APIs are built on top of the framework. In other
words, a distributed gateway. Here is a diagram to show you client calls
API A and API A calls API B/API C and API B calls API D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/images/ms_distributed_gateway.png&#34; alt=&#34;ms_distributed_gateway&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this architecture, every API instance contains functions from the
framework and act like a mini gateway embedded. Along with container
orchestration tools like Kubernetes or Docker Swarm, the traditional
gateway is replaced. As there is no remote calls between API to gateway,
all the cross cutting concerns are addressed in the same request/response
chain. This gives you the best performance for your APIs. Here
is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/tutorials/microservices/&#34;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt;
which implements the above diagram and source code for the four APIs can
be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/networknt/light-java-example&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our framework is built on top of Undertow http core server which is very
light and serves 1.4 million &amp;ldquo;Hello World!&amp;rdquo; requests on my desktop with
average response time 2ms. Is it 44 times faster then the most popular
REST container Sprint Boot with embedded Tomcat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The performance test code can be found in
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/networknt/light-java-example/tree/master/performance&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the above diagram, OAuth2 server is an independent entity and you
might ask if it is a bottleneck. I have written another &lt;a href=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/security&#34;&gt;document&lt;/a&gt;
to address it with distributed JWT token verification and client credentials
token caching and renewal. Basically, the Client module in the framework
caches the client credentials token until it is about to expire then renew
in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, our own OAuth2 server built on top of Light-Java framework is very
fast that it can handle 60K user login to get authorization code per second.
For access token, it can serve about 700 access tokens in a second. It is
also open sourced and can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/networknt/light-oauth2&#34;&gt;https://github.com/networknt/light-oauth2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring is bloated</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/spring-is-bloated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 08:15:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/spring-is-bloated/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, Spring seemed to be the replacement of JEE servers with IoC
container and light weight servlet container as its foundation. Especially
recently, Spring Boot brings in an easy development model and increases
developer productivity dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are two issues or limitations in Spring applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;spring-is-bloated-and-it-becomes-too-heavy&#34;&gt;Spring is bloated and it becomes too heavy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Spring was out, it was only a small core with IoC contain and it was
fast and easy to use. Now, I cannot even count how many Spring Components
available today. In order to complete with JEE, Spring basically implemented all
replacements of JEE and these are heavy components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;most-spring-applications-are-based-on-old-servlet-api-and-it-is-slow&#34;&gt;Most Spring applications are based on old servlet API and it is slow.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue with Spring is due to the foundation of servlet container
which was designed over ten years ago without multi-core, NIO etc in
consideration. There is a little improvement in Servlet 3.1 but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t
right due to backward compatible requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a performance test between Spring Boot and My own Light Java Framework
and Spring Boot is 44 times slower. The performance test code and result can be
found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/networknt/light-java-example/tree/master/performance&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The test result for Spring Boot was based on the embedded tomcat server and
later on I have switched to Undertow servlet container for Spring Boot. The
Undertow Servlet container is faster but still over 20-30 times slower then
Light Java Framework which is built on top of Undertow core http server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 20-30 times difference between the two is due to Servlet overhead and Sprint
Boot overhead and it is very significant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I published the peformance test results, one of the Spring developers pointed
me to a new approach to build Spring Boot application with Netty. The performance
is getting better but still very slow compare with Light Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;memory-footprint&#34;&gt;Memory Footprint&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During these test, I observed that Spring Boot with embedded servlet container uses
at least 5 times more memory. This is a big different in cloud computer as memory is
very expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given above reasons, there is no way that Spring Boot can be used as a
light weight platform for microservices. It is too heavy and two slow. And if you
compare the codebase on both Spring Boot and Light Java, you can see Light Java
code is small and easy to understand without any annotations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservices - The final nail in the coffin for Java EE</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/jee-is-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 08:14:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/jee-is-dead/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When Java was out, big players like IBM, BEA, Oracle etc. saw a great opportunity
to make money as it is a great language for web programming. But how can you make
big money around a programming language? The answer is to build servers on top
of it and make it complicated so big corporations will pay big bucks for it. That
is why we have Java EE specs, JSRs, Weblogic, Websphere and other servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large packages are deployed on these servers that are run so slow and used too
much memory. Development and Debugging within a container was a nightmare for
developers and they usually paid well to compensating the pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of resource usage is too high, you could not find public hosting company
to support Java with a reasonable price tag for a long time. You want to build a
website in Java, you have to pay big bucks for hosting even you might just use a
Servlet container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, Java was used within enterprises and big corporations as only
they can afford million-dollar application servers and well paid enterprise level
developers. I myself have been riding the train since beginning as a Java EE
consultant☺&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2003, Rod Johnson released Spring Framework and it allows IoC and POJO for
development without EJBs. The productivity increment is huge and a lot of
developers jumped onto it and thrown J2EE EJBs out of the window. The application
server vendors saw this and in Java EE 5, they provided some features to make
developer&amp;rsquo;s life easier and less painfull, today’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/spring-is-bloated/&#34;&gt;Spring Framework is so
bloated&lt;/a&gt;
like Java EE containers and it still based on Java EE servlet container which was
designed in 90&amp;rsquo;s without considering multiple cores and NIO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this period of time, PHP was flying. It used less memory and resource and
was well supported by hosting companies. Some CMS platform built on PHP like
WordPress, Drupal etc. drove a lot of open source developers into PHP. Although
PHP is the most popular language these days, it has its shortcomings. It is slow
and hard to make it scalable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2009, Ryan Dahl introduced Node.js that supports asynchronous, non-blocking
and event-driven I/O. This increase the response rate dramatically as the server
threads are well utilized and the throughput of a single server can be comparable
to a cluster of Java EE servers. Node.js is a very good design but it has its
&lt;a href=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/nodejs/&#34;&gt;limitations&lt;/a&gt;.
It is hard to scale and hard to integrate with existing legacy systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, a new player Undertow came in town and it is Java based non-blocking web
server. From techempower.com &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techempower.com/benchmarks/#section=data-r12&amp;amp;hw=peak&amp;amp;test=plaintext&#34;&gt;test&lt;/a&gt;,
it serves millions requests per second
on a single $8000 dell server using the same test case Google claimed to serve
1 million requests with a cluster. It is lightweight with the core coming under
1Mb and a simple embedded server uses less than 4Mb of heap space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new Undertow Core, we&amp;rsquo;ve built &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/networknt/light-java&#34;&gt;Light Java Framework&lt;/a&gt;
which is aiming containerized microserivces. It supports design driven approach
from OpenAPI specification to generate code and drives security and validation
during runtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;java-ee-vendors&#34;&gt;Java EE vendors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years ago, Java EE vendors like Oracle and IBM spent billions dollars to develop their
application servers and these servers (WebLogic and WebSphere) will be sold for millions
dollars to big organizations. Now it is hard to sell these servers as JBoss is grabbing
market share quickly and Oracle is &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.slashdot.org/story/16/07/02/1639241/oracle-may-have-stopped-funding-and-developing-java-ee&#34;&gt;dropping Java EE support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With microservices gainning traction, the application servers are hard to sell as these
servers are used to host monolithic applications. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to host a service
with only 200 lines of code on WebSphere which has several millions lines of code.
99 percent of CPU and memory will be wasted on the Java EE server and your service will be
slow as a snail. This forces them to rebrand and make changes on their platform to allow
user to build microservices but the result is not promising. I have tested JBoss WildFly
Swarm in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/networknt/light-java-example/tree/master/performance&#34;&gt;benchmarks&lt;/a&gt;
and it is at the bottom. WebLogic Multitenant and WebSphere Liberty will be much worse as
they are significant bigger than WildFly Swarm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;java-ee-customers&#34;&gt;Java EE customers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From customer&amp;rsquo;s perspective, it is not worth buying these applications as all the promises
of Java EE are not true. You build an application for WebSphere cannot be deployed on WebLogic
and you have to spend money to upgrade your application to newer version of the application
server as the old version is not supported anymore. And these upgrade cost millions of
dollars plus the cost of the new application servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some smart people start to ask questions. Why we need to deploy our application to these
monster servers? Why we need to package our application as ear or war instead of just a
jar? Why cannot we break the big application to smaller pieces and deploy and scale them
independently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;microservices&#34;&gt;Microservices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer for these questions are microservices. Wikipedia defines microservices as
&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;a software architecture style in which complex applications are composed of small,
independent processes communicating with each other using language-agnostic APIs.
These services are small, highly decoupled and focus on doing a small task,
facilitating a modular approach to system-building.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microservice Architecture make applications easier to build by breaking down application
into services. The services are composable. Each service can be deployed and developed
separately. The services can be composed into an application. The services have the
possibility of being used in other applications more readily. This can speed up
development as services can define an interface and then the services can be developed
concurrently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason services make sense is resilience and scalability. Instead of depending
on a single server and a single deployment, services can be spread around multiple
machines, data centers or availability zones. If a service fails, you can start up
another. Since the application is decomposed into microservices (small services),
you can more efficiently scale it by spinning up more instances of the heaviest used
services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have lived through COM, DCOM, CORBA, EJBs, OSGi, SOAP, SOA etc. then you
know the idea of services and components is not a new thing. The issue with enterprise
components is they assume the use of hardware servers which are large monoliths and
you want to run a lot of things on the same server. We have EJBs, WAR files and EAR
files, and all sorts of nifty components and archives because server acquisition was
a lot more difficult. Well turns out in recent years, that makes no sense. Operating
systems and servers are ephemeral, virtualized resources and can be shipped like a
component. We have EC2, OpenStack, Vagrant and Docker. The world changed. Microservice
Architecture just recognize this trend so you are not developing like you did when the
hardware, cloud orchestration, multi-cores, and virtualization did not exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t use an EAR file or a WAR file when you start a new project.  Now you can run a
JVM in a Docker image which is just a process pretending to be an OS running in an OS
that could be running in the cloud which is running inside of a virtual machine which
is running in Linux server that you don’t own that you share with people who you don’t
know. Got a busy season? Well then, spin up 100 more server instances for a few weeks
or hours. This is why you run Java microservices as standalone processes and not running
inside of a Java EE container, not even a servlet container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microservice generally provide an API endpoint over HTTP/JSON. This allows easy
integration with not only services you build, but any software (open-source or from
vendor) that provides an HTTP/JSON interface. This makes the services consumable and
composable in ways that just make sense. A prime example of this is EC2, S3 and other
services from Amazon (and others). The very infrastructure you deploy on can become
part of the application and is programmable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you design your application to use microservices, you are designing it to be
modular, programmable and composable. This allows you to replace microservices with
other microservices. You can rewrite or improve parts of your larger application
without disruption. When everything has a programmable API, communications between
application microservices becomes easier. (Never trust a microservice that does not
publish access to with curl).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While microservices are getting popular, a lot vendors are trying to re-brand their
Java EE based web services to microservices in order to sell their obsolete product.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/gateway/&#34;&gt;API Gateway&lt;/a&gt; is one of
them. These gateways are designed for Web Services but not Microservices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason Bloomberg, president of Intellyx, talks about the distinction between a typical
web service and a microservice, arguing against the tendency to try to simply rebrand
web services as microservices in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://techbeacon.com/dangers-microservices-washing-get-value-strip-away-hype&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microservices are not Web Services on enterprise service buses (ESBs). And it is not
the traditional service-oriented architecture (SOA), while it inherits some of the
basic principles of SOA, it&amp;rsquo;s fundamentally a different set of practices because the
entire environment has completely transformed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The environment for microservices architecture, in contrast, is the borderless
enterprise: end-to-end, cloud-centric digital applications leveraging fully
virtualized and containerized infrastructure. Containers take applications and
services down to a self-contained, component level, and DevOps provides the framework
for the IT infrastructure and automation to develop, deploy, and manage the
environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microservices don&amp;rsquo;t require containers (or vice versa), but they&amp;rsquo;re easily
containerizable by design. Furthermore, if you&amp;rsquo;re implementing containers,
it&amp;rsquo;s difficult and typically unwise to put any new executable code other than
microservices in them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker and other container technologies are viewed by some as a integral to microservice
architecture and some confuse and conflate containers with microservices. Containers are
minimalist OS pieces to run your microservice on. Docker provides ease of development and
enables easier integration testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Containers are just an enabler to microservices and you can do microservice development
without containers. And you can use Docker to deploy monolithic application. Microservices
and containers like Docker go well together. However, Microservices are a lot more than
containers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As application development style has been changing over the recent years, microservices
are getting more and more popular. Big corporations are breaking their big applications
up to smaller pieces that can be individually deployed and replaced. These smaller
services are deployed within docker containers on the cloud. I myself have been working
on this area for my clients for the last couple of years and devoted my time to build
an open source microservices framework &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/networknt/light-java&#34;&gt;Light Java&lt;/a&gt;
which provides all cross cutting concerns for microservices running in containers. It
supports design driven approach and developers will only focus on the domain business
logic in generated handlers. All the rest will be handled by the Framework and DevOps flow.
So far, it is the fastest microservices framework available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservices</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 08:13:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/light-java/architecture/microservices/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speed and Safety at Scale and in Harmony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re like most software developers, team leaders, and architects responsible for getting
working code out the door of your company, this phrase describes your job in a nutshell. Most
of you have probably struggled at this, too. Getting to market quickly seems to imply giving
up a bit of safety. Or, conversely, making sure the system is safe, reliable, and resilient
means slowing down the pace of feature and bug-fix releases. And “at scale” is just a dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three principals of the microservices architecture style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microservices are ideal for big systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microservice architecture is goal-oriented not solution-oriented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microservices are focused on replaceability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;microservice applications share some important characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small in size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Messaging enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bounded by contexts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Autonomously developed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Independently deployable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decentralized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built and released with automated processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you build software in this way, the cost of controlling and managing output increases
significantly. In a microservice architecture, the services tend to get simpler, but the
architecture tends to get more complex. That complexity is often managed with tooling,
automation, and process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you first begin learning about microservice architecture it’s easy to get caught up in
the tangible parts of the solution. You don’t have to look hard to find people who are excited
about Docker, continuous delivery, or service discovery. All of these things can help you to
build a system that sounds like the microservice systems we’ve been discussing. But
microservices can’t be achieved by focusing on a particular set of patterns, process, or tools.
Instead, you’ll need to stay focused on the goal itself—a system that can make change easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More specifically, the real value of microservices is realized when we focus on two key
aspects—speed and safety. Every single decision you make about your software development ends
up as a trade-off that impacts these two ideals. Finding an effective balance between them at
scale is what we call the microservices way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Speed of Change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Safety of Change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At Scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Harmony&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original intent of the microservice architecture concept—to replace complex monolithic
applications with software systems made of replaceable components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, there are so many stories that big companies built their system in a microservices way.
There are common goals and benefits that emerge from these implementation stories. The goal
of improving software delivery speed as functional scope grows is realized through greater
agility, higher composability, improved comprehensibility, independent service deployability,
organizational alignment, and polyglotism. The goal of maintaining software system safety as
scale increases is achieved through higher availability and resiliency, better efficiency,
independent manageability and replaceability of components, increased runtime scalability,
and more simplified testability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;speed&#34;&gt;Speed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agility allows organizations to deliver new products, functions, and features more quickly and pivot more easily if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Composability reduces development time and provides a compound benefit through reusability over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comprehensibility of the software system simplifies development planning, increases accuracy, and allows new resources to come up to speed more quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Independent deployability of components gets new features into production more quickly and provides more flexible options for piloting and prototyping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organizational alignment of services to teams reduces ramp-up time and encour‐ ages teams to build more complex products and features iteratively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polyglotism permits the use of the right tools for the right task, thus accelerating technology introduction and increasing solution options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;safety&#34;&gt;Safety&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greater e ciency in the software system reduces infrastructure costs and reduces the risk of capacity-related service outages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Independent manageability contributes to improved efficiency, and also reduces the need for scheduled downtime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaceability of components reduces the technical debt that can lead to aging, unreliable environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stronger resilience and higher availability ensure a good customer experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better runtime scalability allows the software system to grow or shrink with the business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved testability allows the business to mitigate implementation risks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>